<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Eric Daniel Fournier</title>
    <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Eric Daniel Fournier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:05:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mindful Decommissioning of Natural Gas Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/mindful-decommissioning-of-natural-gas-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:05:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/mindful-decommissioning-of-natural-gas-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Status Active
Background TBA
Study Area TBA
Results TBA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrification Progress in California</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/electrification-progress-in-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:04:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/electrification-progress-in-california/</guid>
      <description>Status Active
Background TBA
Study Area TBA
Results TBA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Solar Prioritization Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/sgc-solar-pt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/sgc-solar-pt/</guid>
      <description>Status Completed
Background The culimation of this project was the development of what we call the Community Solar Opportunities Mapping (CSOM) tool. This tool is designed to help users identify and prioritize sites for community scale solar generation facilities. CCSC&amp;rsquo;s development team partnered with several local Community Based Organizations (CBOs) who represent the interests of the intended user base of the tool. Interactions with these CBOs were organized into a series of workshops which focused initially on energy system education, then moved onto planning and scoping objectives for the development of the new tool, and finally, concluded with solicitation of feedback on features of the new tool’s prototype and final design stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Energy Communities - Phase II Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-ii/</guid>
      <description>Status Active
Background CCSC is currently working as a sub-contractor to The Energy Coalition (TEC) to develop an &amp;ldquo;Advanced Energy Community&amp;rdquo; within the LA County unincorporated neighborhoods of Bassett and Avocado Heights (BAAEC). This project has a number of components including: the development of a local community solar generation facility whose output will support a Virtual Net Metering program, creation of a set of &amp;ldquo;Advanced Energy Homes&amp;rdquo; which will have a combination of distributed energy resources and electrified appliances, installation of publicly accessible EV charging infrastructure, air-quality monitoring, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disadvantaged Community Energy System Transformations</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-natural-gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-natural-gas/</guid>
      <description>Status Complete
Background Our center has been funded to work on this project under a grant from the California Energy Commission. It&amp;rsquo;s actually quite a unique and interesting project. At the most basic level, it is concerned with understanding the different categories of potential benefits that might be associated with the electrification of the residential energy system. What does that mean? Well, we are (fairly) confident that removing natural gas appliances from homes and replacing them with more efficient, electric versions, will benefit the climate system in terms of reduced greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Energy Communities - Phase I Planning</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-i/</guid>
      <description>Status Completed
Background Our group at the California Center for Sutainable Communities was awarded a grant from the California Energy Commission to develop a comprehensive plan developing an &amp;ldquo;Advanced Energy Community&amp;rdquo; within a disadvantaged portion of Southern California. As part of this project we partnered with team members from The Energy Coalition, a not-for-profit implementer of energy efficiency upgrade programs, and Active San Gabriel Valley, a community based organization which conducts outreach events and engagement activities around the issues of energy, public health, and sustainable transportation solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
