<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Daniel Fournier</title>
    <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric Daniel Fournier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:45:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ericdfournier.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implications of the Timing of Natural Gas Use for Electrification</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/implications-of-the-timing-of-gas-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/implications-of-the-timing-of-gas-use/</guid>
      <description>Journal Environmental Research Letters
Title Implications of the timing of residential natural gas use for appliance electrification efforts
Authors Eric Daniel Fournier, Robert Cudd, Felicia Federico, Stephanie Pincetli
Abstract Current strategies for deep decarbonization of the residential building sector invoke the following three pillars of action: (1) radically improve the efficiency of end-use electricity consumption, (2) shift to 100% renewable generation of electrical grid power, and (3) move aggressively to electrify all remaining fossil fuel end-uses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability-Privacy Tradeoffs in Utility Customer Data Aggregation</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/data-privacy-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/data-privacy-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>Journal Utilities Policy
Title Guidance on the usability-privacy tradeoff for utility customer data aggregation
Authors Benjamin L. Ruddell, Dan Cheng, Eric Daniel Fournier, Stephanie Pincetl, Caryn Potter, Richard Rushforth
Abstract Modern cities, along with their researchers and innovators can benefit from applying &amp;quot; big data&amp;quot; to their sus- tainability and infrastructure problems and policies, e.g., water and energy consumption. Unfortunately, current utility customer data (UCD) privacy rulemaking fails to ensure safe release of these data for the public benefit and does not currently strike a sound balance between the competing values of usability and privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Energy Sufficiency and Residential Energy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/energy-sufficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/energy-sufficiency/</guid>
      <description>Journal Elementa Science of the Anthropocene
Title On energy sufficiency and the need for new policies to combat growing inequities in the residential energy sector
Authors Eric Daniel Fournier, Robert Cudd, Felicia Federico, Stephanie Pincetli
Abstract The decreasing cost and increasing availability of new technologies capable of improving household energy efficiency, generating and storing renewable energy, and decarbonizing major end use appliances have begun to significantly transform many residential communities across the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Solar Prioritization Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/sgc-solar-pt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/sgc-solar-pt/</guid>
      <description>Status Completed
Background The culimation of this project was the development of what we call the Community Solar Opportunities Mapping (CSOM) tool. This tool is designed to help users identify and prioritize sites for community scale solar generation facilities. CCSC&amp;rsquo;s development team partnered with several local Community Based Organizations (CBOs) who represent the interests of the intended user base of the tool. Interactions with these CBOs were organized into a series of workshops which focused initially on energy system education, then moved onto planning and scoping objectives for the development of the new tool, and finally, concluded with solicitation of feedback on features of the new tool’s prototype and final design stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Solar Potential from Urban Rooftops in Los Angeles</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/net-solar-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/net-solar-potential/</guid>
      <description>Journal Energy Policy
Title Net Solar Potential from Urban Rooftops in Los Angeles
Authors Erik Porse, Eric Fournier, Dan Cheng, Claire Hirashiki, Hannah Gustafson, Felicia Federico, Stephanie Pincetl
Abstract Rooftops provide accessible locations for solar energy installations. While rooftop solar arrays can offset in- building electricity needs, they may also stress electric grid operations. Here we present an analysis of net electricity generation potential from distributed rooftop solar in Los Angeles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Energy Communities - Phase II Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-ii/</guid>
      <description>Status Active
Background CCSC is currently working as a sub-contractor to The Energy Coalition (TEC) to develop an &amp;ldquo;Advanced Energy Community&amp;rdquo; within the LA County unincorporated neighborhoods of Bassett and Avocado Heights (BAAEC). This project has a number of components including: the development of a local community solar generation facility whose output will support a Virtual Net Metering program, creation of a set of &amp;ldquo;Advanced Energy Homes&amp;rdquo; which will have a combination of distributed energy resources and electrified appliances, installation of publicly accessible EV charging infrastructure, air-quality monitoring, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy for Water Use in LA</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/energy-for-water-use-in-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/energy-for-water-use-in-la/</guid>
      <description>Journal Environmental Research Communications
Title Energy use for urban water management by utilities and households in Los Angeles
Authors Erik Porse, Kathryn B Mika, Alvar Escriva-Bou, Eric D Fournier, Kelly T Sanders, Edward Spang, Jennifer Stokes-Draut, Felicia Federico, Mark Gold, Stephanie Pincetl
Abstract Reducing energy consumption for urban water management may yield economic and environmental benefits. Few studies provide comprehensive assessments of energy needs for urban water sectors that include both utility operations and household use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grid Vulnerability to Extreme Heat</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/grid-vulnerability-to-extreme-heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/grid-vulnerability-to-extreme-heat/</guid>
      <description>Journal Energy Policy
Title Electricity infrastructure vulnerabilities due to long-term growth and extreme heat from climate change in Los Angeles County
Authors Daniel Burillo, Mikhail V Chester, Stephanie Pincetl, Eric Fournier
Abstract Many studies have estimated the effects of rising air temperatures due to climate change on electricity infrastructure systems, but none have quantified impacts in terms of potential outages down to the neighborhood scale. Using high-resolution climate projections, infrastructure maps, and forecasts of peak electricity demand for Los Angeles County (LAC), we estimated vulnerabilities in the electricity infrastructure to 2060.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Size Growth and Energy Usage</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/home-size-growth-and-energy-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/home-size-growth-and-energy-usage/</guid>
      <description>Journal Applied Energy
Title Effects of building size growth on residential energy efficiency and conservation in California
Authors Eric D Fournier, Felicia Federico, Erik Porse, Stephanie Pincetl
Abstract Many utility and government programs exist to promote energy efficiency (EE) in residential buildings. While programs have succeeded in reducing per square foot energy usage intensity (EUI), they do not necessarily promote conservation, in terms of reduced total energy consumption. Using statistical analysis and data mining techniques, we examined relationships between home size, electricity and natural gas EUIs, and neighborhood level socio-economic attributes among ∼1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disadvantaged Community Energy System Transformations</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-natural-gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-natural-gas/</guid>
      <description>Status Active
Background Our center has been funded to work on this project under a grant from the California Energy Commission. It&amp;rsquo;s actually quite a unique and interesting project. At the most basic level, it is concerned with understanding the different categories of potential benefits that might be associated with the electrification of the residential energy system. What does that mean? Well, we are (fairly) confident that removing natural gas appliances from homes and replacing them with more efficient, electric versions, will benefit the climate system in terms of reduced greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Peak Electricity Demand Under Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/forecasting-peak-electricity-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/forecasting-peak-electricity-demand/</guid>
      <description>Journal Applied Energy
Title Forecasting peak electricity demand for Los Angeles considering higher air temperatures due to climate change
Authors Daniel Burillo, Mikhail V Chester, Stephanie Pincetl, Eric D Fournier, Janet Reyna
Abstract Los Angeles County (LAC) is a large urbanized region with 9.7 million residents (as of 2010) and aging infrastructure. Population forecasts indicate that LAC will become home to an additional 1.2–3.1 million residents through 2060. Additionally, climate forecasts based upon representative concentration pathway (RCP) scenarios 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Energy Communities - Phase I Planning</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/projects/cec-aec-i/</guid>
      <description>Status Completed
Background Our group at the California Center for Sutainable Communities was awarded a grant from the California Energy Commission to develop a comprehensive plan developing an &amp;ldquo;Advanced Energy Community&amp;rdquo; within a disadvantaged portion of Southern California. As part of this project we partnered with team members from The Energy Coalition, a not-for-profit implementer of energy efficiency upgrade programs, and Active San Gabriel Valley, a community based organization which conducts outreach events and engagement activities around the issues of energy, public health, and sustainable transportation solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Genetic Algorithms for Locating Optimal Corridors</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/parallel-genetic-algorithms-for-locating-optimal-corridors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/parallel-genetic-algorithms-for-locating-optimal-corridors/</guid>
      <description>Journal Environment and Planning B: Urban Analytics and City Science
Title MOGADOR revisited: Improving a genetic approach to multi-objective corridor search
Authors Eric D Fournier
Abstract The MOGADOR algorithm is a specialized heuristic approach to the shortest path problem, which employs genetic operators to the search for near optimal corridors within the context of multiple independent objectives. This article expands upon the work contained in the MOGADOR algorithm’s debut publication by introducing a set of refined techniques for initializing the algorithm, which are responsive to the characteristics of the problem specification, the desired runtime, and the global quality of the output solution set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Cylce Energy-Water Efficiency of Treated Water Reuse</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/life-cycle-energy-water-efficiency-of-treated-water-reuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/life-cycle-energy-water-efficiency-of-treated-water-reuse/</guid>
      <description>Journal Environmental Science &amp;amp; Technology
Title Investigating the energy-water usage efficiency of the reuse of treated municipal wastewater for artificial groundwater recharge
Authors Eric D Fournier, Arturo A Keller, Roland Geyer, James Frew
Abstract This project investigates the energy-water usage efficiency of large scale civil infrastructure projects involving the artificial recharge of subsurface groundwater aquifers via the reuse of treated municipal wastewater. A modeling framework is introduced which explores the various ways in which spatially heterogeneous variables such as topography, landuse, and subsurface infiltration capacity combine to determine the physical layout of proposed reuse system components and their associated process energy-water demands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing Impacts to Ecosystem Services from Gas Well Placement</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/minimizing-impacts-to-ecosystem-services-from-gas-well-placement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/minimizing-impacts-to-ecosystem-services-from-gas-well-placement/</guid>
      <description>Journal Journal of Environmental Management
Title Minimizing impacts of land use change on ecosystem services using multi-criteria heuristic analysis
Authors Arturo A Keller, Eric Fournier, Jessica Fox
Abstract Development of natural landscapes to support human activities impacts the capacity of the landscape to provide ecosystem services. Typically, several ecosystem services are impacted at a single development site and various footprint scenarios are possible, thus a multi-criteria analysis is needed. Restoration potential should also be considered for the area surrounding the permanent impact site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectrocopic Investigations of Iron Rich Clays</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/spectroscopic-investigation-of-iron-rich-clays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 08:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/papers/spectroscopic-investigation-of-iron-rich-clays/</guid>
      <description>Journal Langmuir
Title Spectroscopic Investigations of Fe2+ Complexation on Nontronite Clay
Authors Rose B. Merola, Eric D. Fournier, Molly M. McGuire
Abstract Diffuse reflectance (visible) and attenuated total internal reflection Fourier-transform infrared (ATR-FTIR) spectroscopies were used to examine a colloidal nontronite clay in the presence of Fe2+(aq). pH-dependent changes are observed in both types of spectra. In the visible region, a broad feature at ∼750 nm appears as the pH is raised to circumneutral values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Education Bren School of Environmental Science and Management
2010-2015
Santa Barbara, California, USA
Doctor of Philosophy in Environmental Science
University of California at Santa Barbara
2013-2014
Santa Barbara, California, USA
Master of Arts in Geographic Information Science
Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies
2008-2010
New Haven, Connecticut, USA
Master of Science in Environmental Science
Bucknell University
2004-2008
Lewisburg, Pennsylvania, USA
Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science
School for International Training</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.ericdfournier.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ericdfournier.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email efournier at ioes dot ucla dot edu
Note In my current role within the at the Institute of the Environment and Sustainability I am prohibited from advising PhD students. So please do not contact me with these types of requests as I am, unfortunately, unable to accomodate.
Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
